All right. So, what is selection?
Selection is just how a computer makes
decisions. You have to tell it how to do
that ahead of time. Computers aren't
smart enough to figure it out on their
own. You have to tell them how to make a
decision. Um, as an example, we're going
to use one of the examples of an email I
got once. Um, one of my students said,
"Hi, professor. Sorry I didn't make it
to class. It was a really nice day
outside." And um so if we were to model
that decision-making process, uh not
that I endorse it, but if you were to
model that decision-making process, um
you wake up, you look out the window,
and you say, "If it's a really nice day,
skip class. Otherwise, attend class."
I'm not sure how your attendance would
be because there are a lot of really
nice days, but oh well. Um that is how
you think through the process. You take
into consideration all of the facts that
you have to consider. Then you based off
of that you say if this is the case I'm
gonna do this otherwise I'm gonna do
something else. Um, and that is how
selection works.